## **Doug Radi**

SVP of Marketing and Conventional Channel Sales at Charter Baking Company

### Summary

Experienced marketing, sales and general management professional with 16+ years in the consumer packaged goods industry, including the OTC healthcare, snack food, dairy, bakery and organic/natural industries. Professional experience includes 10 years working on the largest Brands in the natural and organic products industry including Silk Soymilk, Horizon Organic and Rudi's Organic Bakery.

### **Specialties**

General Management, Branding, Strategic Planning, Marketing Planning and Execution, Sales, P&L Management, Advertising, Package Design, Public Relations, Cross Functional Leadership, Organic and Natural Foods

### Experience

### SVP of Marketing and Conventional Channel Sales at Charter Baking Company

May 2012 - Present (2 years 3 months)

#### Vice President, Marketing at Charter Baking Company

August 2007 - May 2012 (4 years 10 months)

Responsible for Marketing and Brand Strategy for Charter Baking portfolio, the leading natural and organic bread and baked goods company in the U.S. Brands include Rudi's Organic Bakery, Vermont Bread Company, The Baker, and Matthews All-Natural.

#### Marketing Director - Silk Soymilk at WhiteWave Foods

September 2004 - August 2007 (3 years)

Managed Silk Soymilk business, one of the largest natural product Brands in the US.

#### **Brand Manager at Horizon Organic**

June 2003 - September 2004 (1 year 4 months)

#### Sr Brand Mgr at Frito-Lay

November 1999 - June 2003 (3 years 8 months)

#### Associate Brand Manager at Bayer Consumer Care

July 1997 - July 1999 (2 years 1 month)

### Skills & Expertise

#### **Consumer Products**

**Food** 

**Cross-functional Team Leadership** 

**P&L Management** 

**Market Planning** 

**Advertising** 

**Strategic Planning** 

**Marketing** 

**Customer Insight** 

**Brand Management** 

**Shopper Marketing** 

**Packaging** 

**Marketing Strategy** 

**Brand Architecture** 

**Sales Management** 

**Business Strategy** 

**Inventory Management** 

Grocery

**Brand Development** 

### Education

### Wake Forest University - Babcock Graduate School of Management

MBA, Marketing, 1995 - 1997

### **Colorado State University**

Bachelor's degree, 1985 - 1989

# Doug Radi

SVP of Marketing and Conventional Channel Sales at Charter Baking Company



Contact Doug on LinkedIn